<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MATH 4180</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MATH 4180</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Getting Started</title>
      <link>/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to the Course and Tools
Welcome to the course! Before we start any data science we will get to know each other, the tools we will use, and the policies of the course. If you have any questions about Week 1 materials please post them on Slack (you will soon see what Slack is) under the in-class .
The following is the basic set-up for all tasks required each week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Visualizing Data</title>
      <link>/data-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-viz/</guid>
      <description>Grammar of Graphics &amp;amp; ggplot
This week we will be discussing what qualities makes a graphic legible and how we can use R to implement readability using the Grammar of Graphics.
  Tasks Notes Links Due           -Add links to The Pudding and make it a reading response (https://pudding.cool/) - add ggplot flipbook (https://evamaerey.github.io/ggplot_flipbook/ggplot_flipbook_xaringan.html#1) note: requires computer (not smart device friendly) - top 10 do and don’t for charts (https://guides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Cleaning Data</title>
      <link>/data-clean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-clean/</guid>
      <description>Tidy Data, Data Wrangling &amp;amp; Joins
  Tasks Notes Links Due      Slides</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/materials/</guid>
      <description>Modern Data Science in R by Benjamin S. Baumer, Daniel T. Kaplan, and Nicholas J. Horton. The book is accessible for free. This is the first book of the two main books that we will use for the course.   R for Data Science by Garrett Grolemund and Hadley Wickham. The book is accessible for free. This is the second book of the two main books that we will use for the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/</guid>
      <description>Instructor
Dr. Tracy Bibelnieks (she/her/hers)
tbibelni@d.umn.edu
Office Hours Th 3-4pm CST
Instructor
Kim Mandery (she/her/hers)
mande143@d.umn.edu
Office Hours MWF 12-1:30pm CST</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/policies/</guid>
      <description>Course Objectives At the end of this semester you will be able to:
 perform data visualization, data cleaning, data augmentation and data organization| apply ethical uses of data in using results of data analytic discern appropriate statistical, computational, and modeling approaches to data problems write technical and nontechnical reports of data analytic insights write professional level correspondence to ask questions/gather information give professional level presentations to technical and nontechnical audiences whether in academic or industrial settings  Assessment It is our intent to design assessments that are a source of intellectual curiosity, joy, and learning rather than a source of stress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/schedule/</guid>
      <description>   Week Dates Course Topic Project Component Notes     1 Jan 13-15 Getting Started     2 Jan 18-22 Visualizing Data  MLK: no class M   3 Jan 25-29 Cleaning Data     4 Feb 1-5 Missing Data Team selection    5 Feb 8-12 Ethical Data Submit management timeline    6 Feb 15-19 Modeling: Linear     7 Feb 22-26 Modeling: Classification     8 Mar 1-5 Modeling: Evaluation Metrics Deadline for submission    9 Mar 8-12 Data Storytelling  Spring Break: no class MTu   10 Mar 15-19 TBD     11 Mar 22-26 TBD Begin technical report    12 Mar 29 - Apr 1 TBD     13 Apr 5-9 Personal Websites: Blogdown     14 Apr 12-16 Personal Websites: Netlify     15 Apr 19-23 Interactive Graphics: Shiny Report revision    16 Apr 26-30 Resume Building Presentation practice     May 3-7  Presentations     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
